So before we try our new model and one more recap on the models so far and keep notes of this so we
새 모델을 시도하기 전에 모델에 대해 한 가지 더 알려드리죠 어떻게 되는지 볼 수 있게 메모해두세요
And your excitement can be there while we run our fine tuned model.
미세 튜닝 모델을 작동하는 동안 여러분도 함께 즐기세요
We started with a constant model.
우린 일정한 모델로 시작했어요
We actually started with a random model, but I think we can put that one to bed.
무작위 모델로 시작했지만 그건 이제 Put it로 할 수 있을 것 같아요
That's that was that was silly.
그건 바보 같은 짓이었어요
So a constant model which just guesses the average from the training data set ends up with an error
훈련 데이터 세트에서 평균을 추측하는 상수 모델은 결국 146
of 146.
오류가 되죠
Uh, and we certainly hope that we can do better than 146.
146점보다는 더 잘했으면 좋겠어요
Otherwise, we might as well stick with a constant.
아니면 그냥 계속 만나는 게 나아요
When we used a very simplistic traditional machine learning with basic features, we got 139.
아주 간단한 전통적인 머신 러닝을 기본 기능으로 사용했더니 139개가 나왔어요
Remember that?
기억나요?
Well, I hope random forest, a more sophisticated algorithm that also that looked at the language,
무작위의 숲과 더 정교한 알고리즘이 언어를 살펴보고
the words um, got down to 97.
97개로 줄었길 바라요
This human did a poor job at 127.
이 인간은 56kg으로 형편없었어요
Uh, GPT four.
GPT 4요
Oh, the big guy did very nicely indeed.
덩치 큰 친구가 아주 잘했어요
At 76 and the Bass Llama 3.1, untrained, quantized down to four bits, did an appalling $396 of error.
76위와 배스 라마가 3위예요 1번은 훈련받지 않고 4개로 수량화했는데 끔찍한 396달러의 오류를 냈어요
A much better off just sticking with the constant than using an untrained llama.
훈련받지 않은 라마를 쓰는 것보다 상수를 쓰는 게 훨씬 나아요
The poor thing did not do particularly well at all.
가엾게도 잘 지내지 못했어요
So I go through this one more time so that you have this nicely framed.
이걸 한 번 더 훑어볼게요 그래야 액자가 잘 나오죠
The question is, remember, GPT four is a model that has trillions of weights.
GPT 4의 중량은 수조 단위라는 걸 기억하세요
GPT four had 1.76 trillion GPT four.
GPT 4는 1이었죠 76조 GPT 4요
It's not known, but it's considered to be much more than that.
알려진 바는 없지만 그 이상으로 여겨지죠
So a huge number of weights.
무게가 엄청나죠
Llama 3.1 base has 8 billion weights, and we have reduced them down to four bits.
라마 3요 1기지는 80억 개인데 우린 그걸 4분의 1로 줄였어요
And then we have used our color.
이제 색을 칠해 볼게요
Sorry.
미안해요
Our Lora adapters like 109MB worth of them to to put some extra weights that we can use to adapt.
로라 어댑터에는 109MB가 들어가는데 거기에 쓸 추가 무게를 더하기 위해서죠
Llama lemma 3.1 base, but these are still small numbers, and obviously this is an open source model,
라마레마3요 1베이스지만 여전히 작은 숫자죠 오픈 소스 모델이라
which means it's free to run.
무료로 실행할 수 있어요
So I'm saying all this to set expectations that obviously it's a lot to ask to try and compete with
이런 얘기를 하는 건 기대를 심어주기 위해서예요 개척지에서 일하는 모델들과 경쟁하는
some of these models at the frontier.
건 무리한 요구죠
The thing that you need to be looking out for is, can we do better than traditional machine learning?
우리가 기존의 머신 러닝보다 더 잘할 수 있을지 살펴봐야 해요
Can we do better than a human can?
인간보다 더 잘할 수 있을까요?
Certainly.
물론이죠
Can we do better than constant?
계속보다 더 잘할 수 있어요?
And how do we stack up when we compare ourselves to GPT four?
GPT 4와 우리를 비교하면 어떤 스택이 나올까요?
So the leading frontier model, and we can also compare it to GPT four or mini, um, as well, uh,
최전방 모델이죠 GPT 4나 미니와도 나중에 비교할 수
afterwards.
있어요
So that gives you the context.
그게 맥락을 제공하죠
I hope you have this in your mind.
잘 생각해 보세요
Maybe write down the numbers so you're ready for for what's to come.
앞으로 닥칠 일에 대비해서 숫자를 적어두세요
And it is time for us to head to Colab and to run inference on the the best, strongest checkpoint from
이제 콜랍으로 가서 가장 강력한 체크포인트를 추론할 때입니다 수직화된 오픈
from the the training of our own verticalized specialized, uh, open source model.
소스 모델을 훈련한 결과죠 HDP, HDP, HDP